### **NEHA V. MILLER**

Charlotte, NC | (626) 841-9294 | neha.v.miller@gmail.com | LinkedIn | Github

#### **EXECUTIVE SUMMARY**

A seasoned Full Stack Developer with 7 years of experience with a demonstrated expertise in developing and maintaining web applications, back-end services, and databases. Passionate for searching new solutions and approaches to accomplish greater outcomes.

## **SKILLS**

- ReactJS
- AngularJS
- SQL/NoSQL
- JavaScript
- RESTful APIs

- HTML5/CSS3/SASS
- PHP/Laravel
- Node.js
- Linux
- Git, JIRA

- Jenkins
- Analytical Thinking
- Problem Solving
- Communication
- Agile Methodology

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Full Stack Developer - The Redcliffe Group LLC

December 2021 – Present

- Integrated with multiple Management Systems; potential earnings of 1 million dollars of additional profit within 6 months.
- Redesigned the web application (Bridge) to improve user experience, leading to a user base increase of 40% within a year.
- Collaborated with 2 different development teams on designs, feature improvements, code testing and deployments for 12+ projects.
- Wrote front-end code, back-end code, integrated with 6+ APIs, and utilized multiple CLI tools and configuration GUI's.
- Participated in weekly code reviews with senior developers.
- Resolved over 250 critical software bugs and maintained performance to ensure ongoing operations.
- Designed and optimized database schemas, ensuring efficient data storage resulting in a 20% decrease in page load time.

## Full Stack Developer – The Kotter Group

March 2017 - December 2021

- Led web application development from design to test, up to production deployment and testing in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatibility.
- Advocated Web interaction design best practices, with a focus on consistency and usability.
- Built reusable code and libraries for future use.
- Integrated with different partners using their REST API and SOAP API.
- Worked on both front-end and backend side to optimize existing web technology and create the best possible user experience.

### Computer Programmer (Intern) – Pro-Tek Consulting

January 2017 - March 2017

- Developed new features and implemented new frameworks to release the updated app using Java and Spring-Hibernate.
- Worked with the design, product and backend team to ensure that all requirements of new features are met and backend services were in place to implement UI solutions in the app.

# Web Developer (Intern) - Pixels-Tech

September 2016 - January 2017

- Tested front-end code in multiple browsers to ensure cross-browser compatibility.
- Designing layouts and user interface by using JavaScript, JQuery, HTML and CSS.
- Made a responsive web page using Bootstrap.

### **EDUCATION**

# **California State University, Los Angeles**

July 2016

Masters of Science in Computer Science

## University of Pune, India

June 2014

Bachelors of Engineering in Computer Engineering